Guide to the Yale Dramatic Association Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Dramatic Association records
1900-2004
RU 300
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
93.42
(75 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, financial records, set designs, scrapbooks, show files, programs, scripts, posters, and photographs documenting the administration and production of theatrical works by the Yale Dramatic Association.
Yale University. Dramatic Association
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 40 (YRG 40), Records of Yale clubs, societies, and organizations
Conditions Governing Access
While this collection as a whole is available for research, parts of it may be restricted due to law, university policy or fragility. Any restricted material will be noted as such.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale University Dramatic Association -"the Dramat"- was founded in the 1899-1900 school year at the instigation of Harry Westcott, Class of 1901, and with the help of William Lyon Phelps of the English Department. An undergraduate club, it was Yale's first organization to receive permission from the faculty to present plays in public on a regular basis. Originally, the Dramat's goals were "to study the drama, and once a year to produce a standard English play … of any dramatist who commands the respect of literary men"; but soon after 1900 the Dramat began not only to increase the number of plays it presented each year, but to expand its repertoire to include the masterworks of American and Continental drama. The Dramat's first production, 23 May 1900, was a double bill of the Second Shepherd's Play and a student adaptation of Chaucer's pardoner's Tale; since then it has produced, among other things, the American premieres of Ibsen's The Pretenders (1907), Gogol's Revizor (1908), Tolstoy's The Fruits of Culture (1912), Shakespeare's Troilus and Cressida (1916), Marlowe's Tamburlaine (1919), Euripides' Rhesus (1922), Galsworthy's The Roof (1930), Wilder's The Long Christmas Dinner (1931), Bulgakov's In the Days of the Turbins (1934), Camus' Caligula (1947), Anouilh's Colombe (1953), and, in 1967, the English language premiere of Eugène Ionesco's Hunger and Thirst. The Dramat has also encouraged the efforts of student playwrights. Cole Porter, Steven Vincent Benét, Thornton Wilder, and alumnus Phillip Barry all wrote for the Dramat.
Since its birth, the Dramat has been administered by a board of undergraduate directors who are more or less closely supervised by a faculty advisory board. Day-to-day operations have been overseen by a series of student managers, and artistic direction has been administered jointly by the student Executive Boards and directors they have hired. The Dramatic Association was incorporated in 1909, and, except for the last eighteen months of World War II, it has been in continuous operation since its founding.
Since 1926 the Dramatic Association has housed its productions and its administrative offices in the Yale University Theatre at 222 York Street. The theatre was the gift to Yale of Edward S. Harkness. The donation that built the theatre also created the Yale Department of Drama, now the Yale School of Drama, with which the Dramat has always shared the theatre. Before moving to the Yale University Theatre, the Dramat staged its New Haven productions on the Old Campus, in College Street Hall, in the Yale Bowl, at the New Haven Lawn Club and the Hotel Taft, and in the Hyperion and Shubert Theatres. Beginning in 1907, the Dramatic Association also toured many of its productions. The Dramat has also sponsored the New Haven presentations of various lecturers, theatrical companies, and other special performers. It has also occasionally collaborated with other schools to produce plays (with Vassar, in 1931, for example, and with Sarah Lawrence in 1937). From 1957 to 1974 it sponsored some seventeen Yale Festivals of Undergraduate Drama, playing host to theatre students from all over the United States and Canada.
Dramatic Association alumni have made names for themselves in many professions. Some who have made careers in the theatre and allied arts are Charles Hopkins, '07, Cole Porter, '13, Monty Woolley, '11, Donald Ogden Stewart, '16, John Hoysradt (Hoyt), '26, T. Edward Hambleton, '34, C. Bowen "Sonny" Tufts, '35, James Whitmore, '44, George Roy Hill, '43, Bradford Dillman, '51, James Franciscus, '54, Rex Robbins, '57, George White, '50, Dick Cavett, '58, Peter Hunt, '61, Sam Waterston, '62, Austin Pendleton, '61, John Conklin, '59, and Perry King, '70. Among the Dramat alumni who are famous in other fields are John Farrar, '18, and Chester Kerr, '36, both in publishing, Stewart and Joseph Alsop, '36 and '37, and August Heckscher, '36, all in journalism, S. Dillon Ripley, '36 and Robert Griffith, '36, museum administrators, diplomat William Bullitt, '12, chaplain T. Lawrason Riggs, '10, and academics Sylvan Barnet, '40, Merrill Knapp, '56, and A. Bartlett Giamatti, '60.
In 1922 a group called the Playcraftsmen was formed under the direction of Jack Randall Crawford of the Sheffield English faculty. The Playcraftsmen were intended to complement the Dramatic Association by developing new playwriting and technical talent. The two groups produced separately—though their memberships overlapped considerably—until 1929, when they merged under the Dramatic Association name. The Dramat Papers contain materials pertaining to the Playcraftsmen even before the merger.
Most of the material in the Yale Dramatic Association Archive was moved from the Dramatic Association offices in the University Theatre to Sterling Memorial Library in the summer of 1974, but some material, particularly the first three scrapbooks and the earliest administrative records, appears to have been donated to the library as early as 1911. Materials about the 1960 musical production of Tom Jones were donated by its authors, Austin Pendleton, Peter Bergman, Joseph Matthewson, and Robert Archer. The material from the Dramat had been allowed to accumulate in the University Theatre since 1926, and its condition suggests that it received only sporadic attention there. It is safe to assume that some materials were lost.
Scope and Contents
The papers in the Dramatic Association collection have been arranged to facilitate two kinds of research: research on specific productions of seasons, and research on the operation of the Dramat. Though most information that will inform one kind of research will also, to some extent, inform the other, most materials lend themselves better to one or the other category.
Materials that should help with production research include Dramat scrapbooks, organized chronologically from 1900 to 1954, excluding only the period 1904 to 1906; Dramat production files, organized alphabetically by play title; and the Dramat program file, which contains as complete a set of programs as could be assembled, organized chronologically by season. The scrapbooks (Boxes 1-16) will generally be more useful to the scholar interested in the first twenty-five years of Dramatic Association history than the show files, which are often sparse or nonexistent for those years. Show files (Boxes 17-23) exist for those productions for which unbound material could be obtained; while none of them contains all of the following items, each of them contains at least one: playscripts or prompt copies or the production book for the show, press releases or press clippings, publicity materials, production photos or slides, financial records or correspondence pertaining to the show, rehearsal schedules and production records such as prop lists, set designs, lighting plots or costume sketches, sheet music or special arrangements for productions that utilized music, cast lists, and director's notes. (Similar materials for shows produced before 1925 usually appear in the scrapbooks.) Programs for the shows have been stored separately, in Box 24. Any specific program can easily be found in the folder for the season in which it was used, but the folder listing for Box 24 is also useful either for reconstructing seasons or for locating a play for which there are no show files. Some programs are missing. Of these, some are on file in the Crawford Theatre Collection in Sterling Memorial Library, and when appropriate, a cross-reference to that effect appears in the folder listing. A list of missing programs appears in this register as Appendix I.
At the end of the show files are materials relating to Dramat sponsored Freshman One-Acts, and to shows and lectures presented under Dramat auspices. At the end of the Dramat program file are programs and other materials relating to productions of the Playcraftsmen.
Boxes 25-29 will be of greatest use to the scholar interested in the institutional history of the Dramatic Association. Most important in Box 25 are the minutes of the Dramat Executive and Advisory Boards and the records of the Playcraftsmen from 1922 to 1925. Boxes 26 and 27 contain Dramat financial records, but Box 26 also contains a Manager's Book, compiled in 1904-1905, that sheds invaluable light on early Dramat production methods. Box 28 contains miscellaneous scripts that were submitted (and often rejected) for production at various Dramat Festivals. Box 29 contains historical materials about the festivals.
In addition, Box 29 contains copies of most of the formal agreements between the Dramat and the University, information compiled by various Dramat historians, and what records the Dramat kept of the controversy surrounding the retention of Dramat coach Monty Woolley between 1925 and 1927.
The last several boxes in the collection contain primarily oversized photographs. Box 30 houses group pictures of the Dramatic Association membership for various years, and Box 31 holds oversized production photos.
Additional materials relating to the Yale Dramat can be found in other areas of Manuscripts and Archives, and, indeed, in other parts of the University. Duplicate programs, a series of Dramat-published souvenir playscripts, and additional photos of student plays can be found in the main reading room of Manuscripts and Archives. References to the Dramatic Association can be found in the appropriate files in the papers of Yale's President. The Crawford Theatre Collection, as has been noted, holds some Dramat programs otherwise unavailable. A collection of recordings of Dramat musicals is housed in Historical Sound Recordings, Sterling Memorial Library, and the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library holds materials relating to the productions Cole Porter wrote for the Dramat and to those written for the Dramat by Richard Maltby and David Shire. The Yale Dramatic Association offices retain a collection of Dramat posters.
The Dramatic Association Papers are still a growing collection; the Dramat adds materials at the end of every school year. For information about activities after October, 1976, or financial records later than 1968, consult the Research Archivist.
For more information on the history of the Dramatic Association and the Playcraftsmen, see Terri Elaine Jones, "Undergraduate Drama at Yale" (B.A. Essay, Yale College, 1976), on file in Yale University Manuscripts and Archives. To put the Dramatic Association and the Playcraftsmen in the context of the history of Yale College from 1900 to 1937, the best source is Goerge Wilson Pierson's two-volume history of Yale College.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged as follows: I. Scrapbooks. II. Show Files. III. Programs. IV. Music and Lyrics. V. Administrative Files. VI. Financial Records. VII. Scripts Submitted (Festival). VIII. Yale Dramatic Association Festival Records and Dramat Organizational Material, 1903-1975. IX. Group Photographs. X. Production Photographs; and subsequent Accessions
Appendix 1:
The following programs are not on file in the Yale Dramatic Association Papers in Manuscripts and Archives. Where indicated by an asterisk, copies may be found in the Crawford Theatre Collection in Sterling Memorial Library.
The Magistrate (*) 1904-1905, (Apr)
The Importance of Being Earnest (*) 1907-1908, Jan
Robin of Sherwood (*) 1911-1912, Jun
Twelfth Night 1920-1921, Jun
L'Aiglon 1924-1925, Jun
Out O'Luck 1926-1927, Oct
And for Yale 1936-1937, 1936 Nov
Button, Button 1946-1947
Outward Bound 1950-1951, Oct
The Live Wire 1950-1951, Mar
Men Without Shadows (*) 1963-1964, Nov
Richard III 1964-1965, Nov
Death of Doctor Faust (*) 1965-1966, Nov
Mister Roberts 1965-1966, Feb
3 Penny Opera (*) 1965-1966, Apr, Jun
Shoemaker's Holiday (*) 1966-1967, Nov
Waiting for Godot (*) 1966-1967, Feb-Mar?
Hunger and Thirst (*) 1966-1967, Apr-Jun
The Hostage (*) 1967-1968, Feb-Mar
Twelfth Night 1967-1968, May
Serjeant Musgrave's Dance (*) 1969-1970, Nov
Him (*) 1969-1970, Mar
Oh, What a Lovely War (*) 1970-1971, Nov 12-15 Dec 3-6
Freshman One-Acts 1975
College and school drama, American -- Connecticut -- New Haven; College students -- Societies, etc.; College theater; Theater programs; Theater; Theatrical posters, American; Photographs; Playbills; Slides (photographs); Yale University -- Societies, etc.; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Dramatic Association
- Scrapbooks, Series I
  - Dramat
    - 1900-1903, 1906-1907 (Box 1)
    - 1907-1908 (Box 2)
    - 1908-1909 (Box 3)
    - 1909-1910 (Box 4)
    - 1910 September-1911 June (Box 5)
    - 1911 September-1912 June (Box 6)
    - 1912-1913 (Box 7)
    - 1913-1914 (Box 8)
    - 1914-1915 (Box 9)
    - 1915-1916 (Box 10)
    - 1916-1917 (Box 11)
    - 1919-1924 May (Box 12)
  - Playcraftsmen, 1922-1927 (Box 12)
  - Dramat
    - 1924 June-1934 (Box 13)
    - 1935-1943 (Box 14)
    - 1945 October-1953 May (Box 15)
    - 1953 September-1954 May (Box 16)
- Show Files, Series II
  - All My Sons, 1949 October 20-22 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - The Amazons, 1907 January (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Amphityron 38, 1952 February-March (Box 17, Folder 3-4)
  - And For Yale, 1936 Nov, 1937 Jun, Dec, 1937, 1945 October 4, 5, 6 (Box 17, Folder 5-7)
  - Antony and Cleopatra, 1941 June, 1941 June 17, 18 (Box 17, Folder 8-9)
  - Anyone Can Whistle, 1976 February-March (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Anything Goes, 1973 November-December (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Around the World in Eighty Days, 1934 November 22, 24 1934 December 5 1935 January 11 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Arsenic and Old Lace, 1962 February-Mar, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 13-14)
  - The Assassin, 1946 October 18, 19 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - As You Like It, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 16-17)
  - The Balcony, 1969 February (Box 17, Folder 18-19)
  - The Balcony, 1969 February (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - The Beautiful People (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Beggar on Horseback, 1946 March 21, 22, 23 (Box 17, Folder 22-23)
  - Behind The Beyond, Ghost of Jerry Bundler, St. Bartholomew's Eve, The Stranger, 1914 December-1915 February (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Beyond The Fringe, 1972 April (Box 17, Folder 25-26)
  - The Birds, 1952 May-June (Box 17, Folder 27-28)
  - Bold, Bad Men, 1927 February (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Booth Is Back, 1961 May-June (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Breaking Point, 1965 February (Box 17, Folder 31-33)
  - Brown of Harvard, 1933 March 15, 16 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Button, Button, 1946-1947? (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Caligula, 1947 June 13-17, 1947 June (Box 17, Folder 36-37)
  - Camino Real, 1960 November (Box 17, Folder 38-39)
  - Captain Brassbound's Conversion, 1929 June 15, 18 (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - Caucasian Chalk Circle, 1962 November (Box 18, Folder 1-4)
  - Colombe, 1953 Feb, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 5-6)
  - Comedy of Errors, 1938 June 18, 21 (Box 18, Folder 7-8)
  - Coriolanus, 1927 June (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - The Country Wife, 1965 Apr, May, June (Box 18, Folder 10-11)
  - The Crucible, 1957 November (Box 18, Folder 12-13)
  - Cyrano, 1958 Spring (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Danton's Death, 1958 Oct, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 15-16)
  - Dark of the Moon, 1967 November (Box 18, Folder 17-18)
  - The Death of Doctor Faust, 1965 November (Box 18, Folder 19-20)
  - The Devil's Disciple, 1911 Winter (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - The Downstairs Dragon, 1954 November (Box 18, Folder 22-23)
  - The Effect of Gamma Rays on Man-In-The Moon Marigolds, 1976 March (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Enemies, 1972 February-March (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Fashion, 1947 March 6, 8 (Box 18, Folder 26-27)
  - Fiesco, 1939 June 17, 20 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Finian's Rainbow, 1962 May, tour (Box 18, Folder 29-31)
  - The Fireman's Flame, 1948 June 18, 19, 21 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Free Speech and Great Catherine, 1949 January 20, 21, 22 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - The Frogs, 1941 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - The Front Page, 1937 November (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Fruits of Culture, 1912 December 19-1913 January 25 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - A Funny Thing Happened on the Way to the Forum, 1969 May-June (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - The Golden Boy, 1946 May 21-23, June 22 (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Good Soldier Schweik, 1964 February (Box 18, Folder 39-40)
  - Grand Guignol, 1948 April 29, 30; May 1 (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Grand Tour, 1959 April-May (Box 19, Folder 1-4)
  - The Great Gatsby, 1956 April (Box 19, Folder 5-6)
  - The Hairy Ape, 1941 January 16, 17, 18 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Harold, 1915 June (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Harvey, 1950 November-December (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - The Hasty Heart, 1951 March (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Hay Fever, 1940 March 1 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Hayfoot, Straw Foot, 1942 October 22-24, 26 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Heads you Lose, 1949 November 17, 18, 19, 1949 November (Box 19, Folder 13-14)
  - Henry VI, Pt. III, 1961 November (Box 19, Folder 15-19)
  - Here Comes the Clowns, 1941 April 18, 19 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Here We Go Again, 1939 February 25, March 2-4, April 5 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Here We Go Again, 1939 Spring (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Him, 1970 February-March (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Hippolytus, 1935 June 14-15, 18 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - The Hostage, 1968 November (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - The Hot L Baltimore, 1976 March (Box 19, Folder 25A)
    General
    Removed to Series II
  - Hunger and Thirst, 1967, 1967 April (Box 19, Folder 26-27)
  - An Ideal Husband, 1915 December 18-1916 January 4 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Il Ventaglio, 1910 December-1911 January (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - The Importance of Being Earnest, 1908, 1942 January 22, 23, 24 (Box 19, Folder 30-31)
  - In The Clover, 1947 Nov, 1948 January (Box 19, Folder 32-34)
  - In The Clover (Top of the World), 1947 November (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - In the Days of the Turbins, 1934 March (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - The Inspector-General, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 37-38)
  - The Jew of Malta, 1940 June (Box 19, Folder 39-40)
  - Julius Caesar, 1932 March 5, 7, 8, 1959 November 19-21, 27, 28 (Box 19, Folder 41-43)
  - Kiss The Boys Good-Bye!, 1951 March (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Knickerbocker Holiday, 1946 November 14, 16 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - The Lady's Not For Burning, 1956 Nov, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
  - La Ronde, 1957 Spring (Box 20, Folder 5-6)
  - Leave it to Psmith, 1935 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Let's Do It, 1976 May (Box 20, Folder 7A)
  - Little Mary Sunshine, 1973 February (Box 20, Folder 8-9)
  - Little Murders / House of Blue Leaves, 1975 February 28-March 5 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - London Assurance, 1909 December-1910 January (Box 20, Folder 11-13)
  - Long Christmas Dinner, The Happy Journey, Love and How to Cure It, Such Things Only Happen in Books, 1931 November 25-26, 28 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - The Lower Depths, 1935 December 6 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - The Madwoman of Chaillot, circa 1957 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - The Male Animal, 1949 June (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - The Man Who Came to Dinner, 1951 November (Box 20, Folder 18-19)
  - Mannerhouse, 1949 May 5-7 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - The Massacre at Paris, 1940 October 21-23 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Men Without Shadows, 1963 November (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - The Merry Wives of Windsor, 1909 June (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Merton of the Movies, 1941 November 23, 26 (Box 20, Folder 24-26)
  - Mind the Music, 1949 March 3-5 (Box 20, Folder 27-29)
  - Misalliance, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - The Miser, 1931 June 12-13, 16 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Mister Roberts, 1966 February (Box 20, Folder 32-33)
  - Mixed Company, The Happy Journey…, The Gamblers, A Miracle of St. Anthony, 1955 Fall (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Much Ado About Nothing, 1933 Jun, November (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Oh, What a Lovely War, 1970 November (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Once Upon A Mattress, 1963 April-June (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Once Upon A Mattress (Box 21, Folder 3-4)
  - Othello, 1963 Spring (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Ours, 1917 December-February (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Out O'Luck, 1925-1926 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Outward Bound, 1931 February 3, 10, 1950 October (Box 21, Folder 8-9)
  - Pal Joey, 1974 November-December (Box 21, Folder 10-12)
  - Pantagleize, 1975 November (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Pantagleize, 1975 November (Box 21)
    See also: box 21, folders 52-59
  - Paradise Hotel, 1974 April (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Peer Gynt, 1971 November (Box 21, Folder 16-17)
  - Perfect Alibi, 1932 June 13 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - The Petrified Forest, 1942 August 18-19 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - The Playboy of the Western World, 1963 February (Box 21, Folder 20-21)
  - The Play's the Thing, 1950 June 8-10 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - The Prétenders, 1907 April (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Le Prétexte, 1907 November (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - The Private Secretary, 1932 November (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Quentin Durward, 1914 June 13 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - The Racket, 1930 November 19-20, 22 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Reunion, The March on El Ratan, St. Carlo Saves the Day, 1929 May (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Revizor, 1908 April (Box 21, Folder 29-30)
  - The Rhesus of Euripides, 1922 June 17 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Rhinoceros, 1968 Early Spring (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Richard II, 1950 March 2-4 (Box 21, Folder 33-35)
  - Richard III, 1964 November (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Robin of Sherwood, 1912 June 15 (Box 21, Folder 37-38)
  - Robin of Sherwood, 1912 June (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - Romeo and Juliet, 1970 May-June (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - The Roof, 1930 June 13-14, 17 (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Room Service, 1948 March (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Rope's End, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - Rosencrantz and Guildenstern are Dead, 1970 March (Box 21, Folder 43)
  - The Scarecrow, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 44-45)
  - The Second Shepherds' Play, 1900 May (Box 21, Folder 46)
  - Serjeant Musgrave's Dance, 1969 November (Box 21, Folder 47)
  - The Servant of Two Masters, 1936 June 13, 16-17 (Box 21, Folder 48)
  - Shoemakers' Holiday, 1966 Nov?, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 49-50)
  - Six Characters in Search of an Author, 1952 November 13-15 (Box 21, Folder 51)
  - Pantagleize, 1975 November (Box 21, Folder 52)
  - Music - Pantagleize - French Horn (Box 21, Folder 53)
  - Music - Pantagleize - Trombone (Box 21, Folder 54)
  - Music - Pantagleize - Percussion (Box 21, Folder 55)
  - Music - Pantagleize - Trumpet (Box 21, Folder 56)
  - Music - Pantagleize - Clarinet (Box 21, Folder 57)
  - Music - Pantagleize - Flute (Box 21, Folder 58)
  - Music - Pantagleize - Piano (Box 21, Folder 59)
  - The Skin of Our Teeth, 1951 May, Jun, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
  - The Skin of Our Teeth, 1958 Feb, March (Box 22, Folder 3-4)
  - Sleep of Prisoners, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - So What!, 1955, 1955 Spring (Box 22, Folder 6-8)
  - The Spider, 1942 September 17, 19 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Stoke Hold, Morgenroth, and One Hundred Thousand Dollars, 1937 June (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Stover at Yale, 1954, 1954 Spring/Fall (Box 22, Folder 11-13)
  - The Swan, 1933 November30, December 1, 2 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Tamburlaine, 1919 June (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - The Taming of the Shrew, 1964 June, 1964 April-June (Box 22, Folder 16-17)
  - Tartuffe, circa 1954 (Box 22, Folder 18-19)
  - The Tempest, 1954 February 26-28, March 5, 6 (Box 22, Folder 20)